

# **AVINASH DHUMAL**

ASSOCIATE MANAGER - IT

## CONTACT INFO



+91-779-840-6759



avinash\_dhumal@yahoo.com



LinkedIn Profile



Online Profile



Pune, MH, India

#### **ABOUT ME**

11.4+ years of software architect, design, development, management, and support experience using Azure & AWS Cloud infrastructures. I have developed, managed, and led client, database, and enterprise applications/products on Microsoft Azure, AWS Cloud and Non-Cloud platforms with Microsoft Technology stack. Currently, I am working as Tech Manager and designated as Associate Manager at Pitney Bowes and managing & leading global mailing products called Tier3 & DLA.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### **ASSOCIATE MANAGER - IT** PITNEY BOWES, INC. FEB 2020 - CURRENT



- Leading and managing Tier3 and DLA product operations and automations for global markets.
- Playing a vital role in leading and architecting PBots Self Service portal for automating operational activities.
  - Additionally leading and managing T3Online product development in agile methodologies.
- Playing important role in handling application & server specific vulnerability. Successfully improved Rapid 7 security score from 10+ to 1+.
- Took the charge of managing on premise to AWS migration (completed APAC & EAME regions).
- Currently managing & leading a team of 12 people (6 direct report and 6 in-direct report) and responsible for their KRA, annual goals and performance appraisals.

# **ASSISTANT MANAGER - IT FLEX**



#### JUN 2015 - FEB 2020

- Delivered 3 major releases and more than 50+ sprints successfully on production over a span of 4.5 years.
- Successfully led automated order processing (EDI) worth revenue of ~10 million dollars.
- Managed major release (FY 2018-19) & achieved more than ~110 million-dollar ROI.
- Played scrum master role and managed a team of 6 people (direct report) and driven projects in AGILE methodology using Azure DevOps and was responsible for their KRA, annual goals and performance appraisals.

#### **SKILLS**

#### **TECHNOLOGIES** ASP.NET ASP.NET C# Core VB.NET Web API SQL Server Services WCF HTML5/ Services CSS3 Angular **j**Query TypeScript 11-13

— TOOLS			
10023			
TFS	GitLab	Jia	Azure DevOps
Service Now	Remedy	Pager Duty	Jenkins
MS Projects	MS Visio	Wireframe Sketcher	Lucid Charts
Checkmarx			

#### **CLOUD PLATFORMS**

Azure AWS

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER (LEAD) L&T INFOTECH

**LT1** 

#### MAY 2014 - JUN 2015

- Involved in collecting requirements for Elevator business and led & designed electronic service dashboard for Otis Elevator customers using ASP.NET, VB.NET and SQL Server 2012, HTML 5, jQuery, bootstrap, CSS3.
- Documented requirement provided by end customers and designed wireframes, functional specs to finalize UI design and system requirement specifications.
- Driven Performance tuning and UAT testing with stakeholders.
- Led a team of 12 people. (10 Developers & 2 Testers)

### SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER HEXAWARE TECHNOLOGIES DEC 2010 - MAY 2014



- Successfully provided production support for AMPS products for the client EY.
- Successfully automated functional/core processes to support critical business requirements of Identity and Access Management domain.
- Designed application code to support end user requirement/business requirement using ASP.NET, C#, SQL Server 2010, jQuery, CSS.
- Assisted in the research, analysis, problems, and coordination of department staff.

#### **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Engineering - I.T.

Diploma - I.T.

Pune University

MSBTE, Mumbai

JULY 2010

JUNE 2007

70.17 %

65.13 %

S. S. C.

Pune Vidyapeeth

**JUNE 2004** 

72.80 %

#### PROJECT 1

# TIER3, DLA, T3ONLINE, AWS CLOUD MIGRATION & VULNERABILITY ASSESSMENT PITNEY BOWES, INC.



#### **2020 - CURRENT**

- Responsible for leading and managing Tier3 and DLA product operations and automations for global markets.
- Responsible for implementing ITIL processes for smooth operations.
- Responsible for leading and architecting PBots Self Service portal for automating operational activities.
- Responsible for leading and managing T3Online product development in agile methodologies.
- Responsible for handling application & server specific vulnerability. (Internal and external)
- Managing On Prem to AWS migration which includes estimation, planning, forecasting, and reporting. (Completed APAC & EAME regions)
- Currently managing & leading a team of 12 people (6 direct report and 6 in-direct report) and responsible for their KRA, annual goals and appraisals.

TECHNOLOGIES			
ASP.NET Core, ASP.NET MVC, C#.NET, Web API, SQL Server 2019, Windows Services, Web Services, WCF, Bootstrap 4.0, Angular 13, TypeScript, jQuery, HTML5/CSS3			
MANAGERIAL SKILLS			
Resource Planning, forecasting & allocation, OKRs, SWOT Analysis, Conflict Management, Risk Assessment, Reporting			
FAMILIAR			
MS Projects, MS Visio, Jira, TFS, GitLab, Remedy, Checkmarx, Jenkins, Ansible, Terraforms, CI-CD, AWS - EC2, Fargate, Container Services, S3 Bucket, Backups, Vaults, CloudWatch, MGN Service, Cloud Endure, Lambda Function, Athena, SMS Service, VPC, Subnets, Security Policies			

#### PROJECT 2

# COMMAND CENTER FLEX



#### 2015 - 2020

- Played agile scrum master role and responsible for solution architect and delivery of the product by leveraging Azure DevOps & CI/CD pipeline.
- Involved in requirement gathering to collect Supply Chain Management business.
- Delivered 3 major releases and more than 50+ sprints successfully on production over a span of 4.5 years.
- Successfully led automated order processing (EDI) worth revenue of ~10 million dollars.
- Managed major release (FY 2018-19) & achieved more than ~110 million-dollar ROI.
- Developed applications in .NET stack and on Azure platform.
- Played scrum master role and managed a team of 6 people (direct report) and driven projects in AGILE methodology using Azure DevOps and was responsible for their KRA, annual goals and appraisals.

TECHNOLOGIES
ASP.NET MVC, C#.NET, SQL Server 2019, Bootstrap 4.0, Angular 13, TypeScript, jQuery, HTML5/CSS3
MANAGERIAL SKILLS
Scrum Master, Resource Planning, forecasting & allocation, OKRs, SWOT Analysis, Conflict Management, Risk Assessment, Reporting
FAMILIAR
TFS, Azure DevOps, CI-CD, Checkmarx, MS Visio, ServiceNow, Azure - Web Roles, Worker Roles, Web Apps, Azure Functions, Blob, Queues, Tables

#### **PROJECT 3**

### ESERVICE 2.0 L&T Infotech 2014 - 2015



- Involved in requirement gathering to collect/understand Elevator business.
- Documented new requirements provided by end customers and designing draft sketches to finalize UI design for the end customer.
- Designed and maintained application code to support end user requirements.
- Assisted with the technical and functional knowledge of the team during the development and/or maintenance of the software product.
- Effectively handled client calls/issues irrespective of geographic Locations.
- Managed & Led team of 12 people for redesign project.

TECHNOLOGIES			
ASP.NET MVC, C#.NET, VB.NET, SQL Server 2012, Bootstrap 2.0, jQuery, HTML5/CSS3			
MANAGERIAL SKILLS			
Scrum Master, Resource Planning, forecasting & allocation, Risk Assessment, Reporting			
FAMILIAR			
TFS, MS Visio, Wireframes, Lucid			

#### **PROJECT 4**

### AMPS (Account Management & Provisioning System) Hexaware Technologies



#### 2010 - 2014

- Successfully implemented interface programs to interact with other platforms and enhance overall functionality of an application.
- Successfully automated core functionality of an application to support business critical aspects.
- Designed SQL scripts to automated workflow which reduced overall cost of resolution and SLA agreed.
- Resolved end user queries/issues in Application at L3/L4 level within defined SLAs.

	TECHNOLOGIES	
ASP.NET, C#.NET, SQL Server 2012		
	FAMILIAR —	
TFS, Remedy, ERT, ORT, ITIL Processes, Outage handling		

#### **AWARDS**

DECEMBER 2021	Q	Ace Award	Pitney Bowes, Inc.
2021	7.	Leading and effectively managing Tier3 AWS migration and innovating automation tools.	
MARCH 2021	Q	Star Award	Pitney Bowes, Inc.
	<b>~ ·</b>	Leading and effectively managing Tier3 and DLA product operations & team and taking smooth hand over of knowledge transition from vendor.	
FEBRUARY 2018	Ö	Gateway – The leaders League	flex
2010	7 +	Leadership Training Program (6 months program)	
OCTOBER 2017	Q	Titanium Award	flex
	7.	Designed a self-service web portal and automated all production cases for quicker response. Reduced overall MTR.	
SEPTEMBER 2016	Q	Platinum Award	flex
2010	7 +	Designed SQL Deployment Tool for automatic SQL deployments.	
AUGUST 2014	Ö	Spot Award	L&T Infotech
		For quick understanding of OTIS elevators business and designing outstanding functional requirement specifications.	
SEPTEMBER 2012	Q	Ace Award	Hexaware Technologies
2012	7 *	For effectively handling AMPS production support applications and clients.	